CHAITANYA KAPOOR

□ chaitanya.7.kapoor@gmail.com

github.com/ckapoor7

□ ckapoor7.github.io

(Nationality: Citizen of the United States of America)

Research Interests

My research interests lie at the intersection of Deep Learning and Neuroscience, aiming to understand and reverse engineer neural computation. I aim to develop computational models of such neural circuits, with an overarching goal of designing efficient, biologically-constrained learning algorithms.

Education

University of California, San Diego

Incoming

Post-Baccalaureate Student (NeuroML Group)

La Jolla, CA

Advisor: Meenakshi Khosla

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Jan. 2024 - July 2024

Visiting Student (Senseable Intelligence Group)

Cambridge, MA

Thesis: LUMIN: Light-sheet Microscopy Analysis Unified with Distributed and Domain-Randomized

Generative Models

Advisor: Satrajit Ghosh

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

Nov. 2020 - July 2024

B.E. (Hons.) in Electrical and Electronics engineering

Pilani, India

Honors & Awards

04/24 NeuroMatch Academy: Computational Neuroscience Summer School

02/24 COSYNE 2024: Undergraduate Travel Grant Award

04/23 OxML 2023: ML × Health Summer School, Oxford Mathematical Institute

Publications

Multiplexed Expansion Revealing for Imaging Multiprotein Nanostructures in Healthy and Diseased Brain

J. Kang, M. Schroeder, Y. Lee, C. Kapoor, E. Yu, T. B. Tarr, K. Titterton, M. Zeng, D. Park, E. Niederst, D. Wei, E. S. Boyden

[Under review - Nature Communications]

RnR-ExM: Robust Non-Rigid Registration Challenge for Expansion Microscopy Volumes E. Besier, R. Zhang, Y. Bando, Y. Quéméner, C. Kapoor, M. Alawi, M. Hoffman, A. Dalca, A.

Casamitjana, I. Arganda-Carreras, E. S. Boyden, H. Pfister, D. Wei

IEEE International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (IEEE ISBI), 2023 - website

Attention-enabled Deep Neural Network for Enhancing UAV-Captured Pavement Imagery in Poor Visibility

C. Kapoor, A. Warrier, M. Singh, P. Narang, H. Puppala, R. Srinivas, A. P. Singh IEEE Multimedia Information Processing and Retrieval (IEEE MIPR), 2023 - paper

Fast and Lightweight UAV-based Road Image Enhancement Under Multiple Low-Visibility Conditions

C. Kapoor, A. Warrier, M. Singh, P. Narang, H. Puppala, R. Srinivas, A. P. Singh PerCom Workshops (PerSASN 2023) - paper

Dense Residual Networks for Gaze Mapping on Indian Roads

C. Kapoor, K. Kumar, S. Vishnoi, S. Ramanathan preprint

Research Experience

Senseable Intelligence Group

Jan. 2024 – Present

Supervisor: Prof. Satrajit Ghosh

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Developed a distributed framework for large-scale ($\sim 1 \mathrm{TiB}$) image segmentation for light-sheet microscopy images.
- Designed a domain-randomized generative model, using spherical harmonics to synthesize cortical sections of *ex-vivo* human brains to enable zero-shot segmentation.
- Worked on designing few-shot, spatially guided semantic segmentation algorithms for MRI segmentation.
- Proposed the use of a topologically aware Graph Neural Network which is capable of encoding spatial and anatomical constraints.

Talmo Lab May 2023 – Present

Supervisor: Dr. Talmo Pereira

Salk Institute, La Jolla, CA

- Working on the development of methods for pose estimation and tracking to quantify animal behavior through robust tracking of anatomical landmarks in 3D.
- Designing algorithms utilizing projective geometry to create inputs for a CNN that leverages geometric reasoning.

Synthetic Neurobiology Group

Feb. 2022 - Jan. 2024

Supervisors: Prof. Ed Boyden, Prof. Donglai Wei

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Worked on the development of a *generalist* 3D segmentation model for Expansion Microscopy (ExM) volumes for various animal species.
- Proposed a human-in-the-loop feedback learning mechanism, built on top of an existing deep learning framework, NucMM.
- Worked on developing a new joint-intensity and point-based, high throughput image registration algorithms having nanoscale precision (10 40 nm) for Multiplexed Expansion Revealing (multiExR). This work is currently under review at Nature Communications.

Camera Culture Group

August 2022 - Dec. 2023

Supervisor: Dr. Ramesh Raskar

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA

- Worked on extracting environments from surfaces of glossy objects from sparse, and unstructured views.
- Explored methods that incorporate shape priors, which enable us to turn everyday objects having unknown geometry into radiance-field camera to image the world from an objects perspective.

Invited Talks and Tutorials

02/24 Automating behavior quantification using deep learning, COSYNE 2024

06/23 SIS Symposium, Harvard SEAS, Seeing Beyond the Camera

Teaching Experience

Department of Mathematics, BITS Pilani

 $\mathbf{August\ 2023-Dec.\ 2023}$

Teaching Assistant

Pilani, India

• Undergraduate TA: assisted with the course Combinatorial Mathematics (MATH F421)

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C, MATLAB, Unix Shell Scripting, LATEX

Technologies/Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, PyTorch, Git, OpenCV